GOVERNOR Eberhart, Adolph O.:
Minnesota Historical Society
Records of Governor Adolph O. Eberhart,
1909-1915.
Minnesota Historical Society
Minnesota. Governor (1909-1915: Eberhart).
General correspondence, correspondence concerning pardon matters, subject files, correspondence with organizations, materials relating to tax-forfeited property and to back taxes owed by railroads and telephone companies, and campaign statements and miscellany from Eberhart's reelection campaign (1913).
10.5 cu. ft. (10 boxes and 2 partial boxes).
CATALOG HEADINGS
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the Minnesota Historical Society. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Topics:
Associations, institutions, etc.--Minnesota.; Escheat--Minnesota.; Governors--Minnesota--Election.; Pardon--Minnesota.; Railroads--Taxation--Minnesota.; Real property tax--Minnesota.; Tax forfeiture--Minnesota.; Telephone companies--Taxation--Minnesota.
Places:
Minnesota--Politics and government--1898-1918.
Persons:
Eberhart, Adolph Olson, 1870-.
ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION
Accession Information:
Accession number(s): none
DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE RECORDS
- General Correspondence (File 646a)
  - General Correspondence, 1909-1910: (58)
    - A-R., 1 folder.
    - S-Z., 13 folders.
  - General Correspondence, 1911-1913, A-C., 16 folders. (59)
  - General Correspondence, 1911-1913, D-Harris., 19 folders. (60)
  - General Correspondence, 1911-1913, Harrison-L., 18 folders. (61)
  - General Correspondence, 1911-1913, M-Q., 19 folders. (62)
  - General Correspondence, 1911-1913, R-U., 17 folders. (63)
  - General Correspondence, 1911-1913, V-Z., 14 folders. (64)
  - General Correspondence, 1914-1915, A-B., 8 folders.
  - General Correspondence, 1914-1915, C-L., 20 folders. (65)
  - General Correspondence, 1914-1915, M-S., 20 folders. (66)
  - General Correspondence, 1914-1915, T-Z., 10 folders. (67)
- File 646c
  - Pardon Matters, 1909-1914, A-Z., 9 folders. (67)
  - Subject Files, 1913-1914:
    - Alfalfa, 1914.
    - Battle of Gettysburg Commission, 1912-1913.
      Includes a list, with address, unit, and GAR post, of Gettysburg veterans. [See also report regarding the 1897 dedication of the Minnesota monument at Gettysburg, filed with records of Governor Clough.]
    - Cattle Production, 1913-1914.
    - Extension Work, 1913.
    - Hog Cholera, 1914.
    - Interest Rates in Minnesota, 1913-1914.
    - Mississippi River Improvement, 1913-1914.
    - Norway Centennial, 1913-1914.
      "Statement by the Governor," [1913]. (The original file with this title was found to be missing from the box, 7/11/2000. The governor's statement was found in a "Miscellaneous" file of Governor Clough.)
    - Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1911-1915., 2 folders.
      (A portion of this file was transferred from "Correspondence, Organizations" in Box 69.)
    - Swamp Land Matters, 1913.
      Correspondence regarding the status of the state's swamp land claims and the funds derived from their sale. Accompanied by a Public Examiner "Report on State Swamp Lands" (1908, typed ribbon copy).
  - Deeds of Forfeited Tax Property, 1909., 1 folder. (68)
  - Certificates of Back Taxes, 1909-1928., 1 folder.
    For railroads and telephone companies.
  - Certificates of Back Taxes, 1910-1914, A-Z., 11 folders.
    Railroads and telephone companies; also correspondence re expirations of redemption for privately held land parcels.
  - Deed of forfeited tax property, M. Laakkonen, Virginia, MN, 1914., 1 folder.
    [box part empty]
- Correspondence, Organizations (File 646e)., 12 folders.
  - A - U, 1909-1910. (69)
  - Academy to American Red Cross, 1911-1913.
  - American Road to Au.
    [For Battle of Gettysburg Commission, originally in this folder, see Box 67.]
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1911-1913.
  - Dramatic to International Dry Farming Congress, 1911-1913.
  - International Conference to Mississippi, 1911-1913.
  - Mothers Day to National F, 1911-1913.
  - National H to Pan American, 1911-1913.
    [For Panama Pacific Exposition, originally in this box, see Box 67.]
  - Permanent to United Spanish War Veterans, 1911-1913.
  - United States to Y, 1911-1913.
  - American A to American P, 1914.
  - American R to M, 1914.
  - National to W, 1914.
- Unnumbered files
  (Found among miscellaneous records of the Governor's office)
  - Conservation and Agricultural Development Congress, 1912. (69)
    Relating to appointment of delegates.
  - Lists of Delegates to Various Conferences, 1909-1913.
  - Recommendations Received Relating to Minneapolis Municipal Court Vacancy, 1912.
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1913.
  - Campaign Statements and Miscellaneous Campaign Materials, 1913.